Mining sits at the foundation of Bitcoin.
NATHANIEL POPPER, AUTHOR, DIGITAL GOLD コイン採掘は、ビットコインの基盤です。
Initially people who were
もともと、ビットコイン ソフトを実行していた人たちは、
running a bitcoin software and
そのコインの発掘競争で勝とうと
trying to win the bitcoin mining race
していました。かなり熱狂的で、
were the sort of fanatics who had fallen in love with this idea
そのアイデアと恋に落ちていたといってもいい。
Overtime Bitcoin mining has essentially become a specialized profession.
そして時がたち、ビットコイン採掘は、 基本的に専門的な職業となってしまいました。
available to people who have some ability to setup these installation around the world. And so
その設備を用意できる人だけがメリットを享受できます。
Mining has increasingly become the specialized profession
いまのどんどん コイン採掘は、専門的な職業となってきました。
that's  become something of problem because
それはある問題を引き起こしています。
the design of bitcoin software gives
ビットコインソフトウェアは、その設計上
decision making power to the miners
コイン採掘者へ意思決定の力を与えていて
And whatever software they choose to run
彼らが実行することを選択したソフトウエアが
that becomes the software and rules for  essentially the whole network.
基本的にネットワーク全体のソフトウェアでありルールになってしまうからです。
So these miners around the world has a sort of
したがって、これらのビットコイン採掘者は、ある意味
voting power over  what the Bitcoin software and what the Bitcoin itself looks like
ビットコインがどんなソフトウェアか、 どのように見えるのかを決める議決権があるといえます。
TRUST DISRUPTED BITCOIN AND BLOCKCHAIN ECHCRUNCH ORIGINALS
信用の破壊的創造 ビットコインとブロックチェーン TechCrunchのORIGINALS
2. BITCOIN MINES AND MINERS 2100 MIL
2.ビットコイン鉱山と鉱夫たち
21 Millions:Final number of Bitcoins to be released by 2140
2100万：最終的に2140年までにリリースされるビットコインの数
12.5 : Bitcoins released onto the network every 10 minutes in 2017
12.5：2017年に10分ごとにリリースされるビットコインの数
So when Satoshi Nakamoto came up with it The real key question is howto get these 21 million outthere.
なかもと さとし がそれを思いついたとき、 本当の重要な問題は、これらの2100万コインとを どうやって配布するかでした。
if he all give it to himself , he would have huge burden.
彼はすべて自分自身に与えた場合、彼は巨大な負担になるでしょう。
**  he gives to the men of the world or to the women, to the children, to the American, to the poor people in Africa and starving people or to the Communists
アフリカの貧しい人々_と飢え人々や共産主義に、アメリカ人に、子どもたちに 、世界中の男性に、または女性に与えたら、どうなるか。
who do you choose  to give 21 million.
あなたなら 誰にこの2100万を 渡すでしょうか。
only fair he came up with was to give it for free to whoever wants it.
彼が思いついた唯一の方法は、それを望んでいる 人には誰にでも自由にそれを与えることでした。
Miner's job is to take all of the valid transactions they see
鉱夫の仕事は、彼らに見えるすべての有効なトランザクションのすべてを受け取り、
and gather up these transactions in what called blocks.
とブロックと呼ばれる単位にこれらのトランザクションを集約させます。
and they perform this busy work. They are kind of in a race *install* the other miners
そして、彼らは 非常に負荷の高い処理を行うのです。 他の鉱夫たちとある種の競争をするのです。
to have the privilege of being the cannonical record of transactions that happened.
そして、それに勝つと、自分のデータが正規の取引記録となる特権を得、
if they win their race. Then there is a very special transaction begining of every single block awards brand new Bitcoins.
そうすると　特別な取引記録が各ブロックの先頭に追加されます。 そえは、まったく新規に生まれたビットコインの取引記録です。
As Bitcoin price rises,
ビットコインの価格が上昇すると、
it incentivises somebody to turn on mining equipment somehere in the word.
それは世界のどこかの人が、新しい 採掘用のコンピューター装置を 起動させるインセンティブになります。
then , that adds this processing power to the netowork which is seen by system.
そして、それは 処理パワーの追加が ビットコインネットワークに行われたということです。
so the system makes an adjustment to make it harder to produce Bitcoin.
すると　このシステムは、次の ビットコインを生成するのを すこし困難にするような調整をするのです。
In my same power footprint here I produce essentially less and less Bitcoin overtime.
ここで私の同じ演算パワーを使うことで、 本質的に 私は生み出すことができるビットコインが、日に日に少なくなります。
But the value of Bitcoin rises.
ただし、個々のビットコインの価値も上昇するのです。
We reach the point where the determining factors and who can profitabily mine  bit contins
我々はすでに 、どんなひとたちが、 利益をあげながら採掘できるのか を決定的する要素が確定した地点にまですでにたどり着いてしまいました。
is access to cheap computer hardware and access to cheap electricity
それは、安いコンピュータハードと安い電力にアクセスできる人たちです。
And Right now ,the place where  those 2 things are easiest to find is China.
今、これらの2つのことを見つけるのが最も簡単な場所は中国です。
And so , you have essentially 2/3 to 3/4 of all of Bitcoins being  mined in the world
それで、基本的に世界で採掘されるビットコインの2/3から3/4は、
going to these mining  installations around China.
中国のにある発掘専用の設備に行ってしまいます。
Min Jian River
岷江（みんこう）
ZHU REI, CEO,UNIDENTIFIED BITCOIN MINE,SZEHUAN PROVINCE There are fifteen people working in this facility.
ZHU REI、最高経営責任者（CEO）、どこかのビットコイン鉱山、四川省 15人の人間がこの施設で働いています。
Their job   is to look after all the hardware here.
彼らの仕事はここのすべてのハードウェアの世話をすることです。
All of them live and work in the power plant.
みんな発電所に住み、働いています。
THose parts of the country with cheaper energy rates are in remote areas, not in the cities.
安価な電力がある場所は都市ではなく、田舎にあります。
So people don't really know where these miners are.
このビットコイン鉱山が どこにいるかは、だれも知りません。
Competition is really intense in China,
競争は、中国では本当に激しいです。
and the number of people here getting into Bitcoin mining is rising rapidly.
ビットコイン採掘に参入する人々の数はここ最近、急速に増えています。
So, the bottom line is, when you are lucky enough to be in a place like this,
もしあなたが、十分にラッキーで こういう電力がとても安い場所に
well, you keep it to yourself.
それを内緒にすることです。
They essentially by having majority mining power  they  hold all the cards for
彼らは基本的に大多数の採掘力を有することにより、
whose transactions getting included that's  another big one. Think about that.
だれの取引記録をブロックに含めるかを 決定するすべてのカードを持つことになります。 これは大きな問題です。
Think about the possibility that due to maybe a government or ruling or something.
例えば、こんな可能性について考えてみてください。 政府や規制か何かのために
No transactions originating in the  US  for Bitcoin should be accepted any of the blocks in China.
米国発のいかなるビットコイン取引は、中国のブロックにふくめることができない。とかね。
That's a very scary scary concept.
それは非常に怖い怖い考えです。
It should be extremely scary to the people who ve invested in businesses that are built on Bitcoin blockchain.
これは、特に ビットコインのブロックチェイン上に構築されている ビジネスに投資した人々には非常に怖いことでしょう。
On the side debates that you also see what you are talking about China,
そのような中国で起こっていることの別の議論もあります。
A question within the Bitcoin comminuty about the roles of miners play in China,
ビットコイン コミュニティで起こっている中国のコイン採掘の役割に関する 疑問があります。
adn whether or not there  should be some sort of concern for some attempts to counteract the growing power of China in mining space.
どんどん大きくなる中国でのビットコインの採掘力を弱める 試みを
in Bitcoin blockchain itself.
するべきかどうか、とういうことです。
It does raise very interesting issue around governance models of public  blockchain.
これは、公開型ブロックチェインのｌ管理モデルに関してとて も興味深い問題を提起します。
What do you do in the situation where one particular entity or a group of entity acting collectively,
もし、あるオープンなシステムで、特定の組織または、協働している組織のグループが
gain enough power in a open system that  they can begin  dictating the governance of  system.
システムの支配を操作することができるほど 十分な力をもっているとしたらどうしますか。
It's something of a test for the philosophy behind this technology.
このある意味、このテクノロジーの背後にある哲学に対するテストの ような気がします。
I mean one of the basic ideas here  was that
この基本的なアイデアの１つは、 もし人々が協力して働けば、 より良いシステムをつくるごとができる そして、
people working together could create a better system and could create a better software.
よりよいソフトウエアができる ということです。
then any one start up or enteprenuer could
そうしたら、どんなスタートアップでも起業家もそれができる。
I mean this was an idea of communal wisdom or hive mind
私は、これが共同の知恵とか、協働意識 の考え方で、
would be   more successful than anybody working in isolation.
孤立して働くよりも、より成功するというアイデアです。
It is not at all  clear that  that  software being  developed by volunteers all around the world
世界中のボランティアによって開発されているこのソフトウェアが
is going to be able to  adapt quickly enough to keep up with this existing powers
この実験のために使われているこれらのパワーや資産に対して十分迅速に対応できるよかどうかは、
and all the resouces that  they have  put in the experiment.
全く明らかではありません。
BAsed on nathaniel Popper's Digital Gold
ナサニエル・ポパーのデジタル金貨に基づいて作成